Sumit Barua

Student

Contact

Address

1210 Oliver Ln Rm 321, Kalamazoo, Ml, 49008

Phone

(269) 276-6993

E-mail

sumitbarua243@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/sumitbarua/

Skills

- Software applications
- Project planning
- Continuous improvement techniques
- Agile environments
- Web app development
- Office 365

A versatile, collaborative, accomplished, and knowledgeable senior Computer Science major currently attending Western Michigan University, with 1.5+ years of work experience. Aiming to leverage a proven knowledge of database management, web development, and programming skills to successfully meet company goals and demands. Possess verifiable leadership, interpersonal, and communication skills that help put across things with a crisp point.

Education

Aug 2018 – Apr 2022

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Western Michigan University - Kalamazoo, MI

- Received Diether Haenicke Scholarship
- Member of Alpha Lambda Delta

Work History

Jun 2021 – Aug 2021

Software Engineering Intern

Frontier Communications, Allen, TX

- Collaborated with software engineers to develop and test application procedures for system efficiency.
- Designed and developed application called Network Quality
 Analyzer to provide automated real-time network information to Customer Support Team for speedy service.
- Got exposed to materials including but not limited to Docker,
 JIRA, and Machine Learning.
- Developed personal and organizational leadership skills.

Jan 2020 -Current

Information Technology Student Assistant

Western Michigan University, Kalamazoo, MI

- Answer user inquiries regarding computer software or hardware operation to resolve problems.
- Install and perform minor repairs to hardware, software, or peripheral equipment, following design or installation specifications.
- Confer with staff, users, and management to establish requirements for new systems or modifications.